

Applicant for:

# **Software Engineer (PHP/ C#/.NET)**

Starboard Asia Co.,ltd. 8 May 2020

# Nguyễn Tài Hạnh

Main interests: PHP, MySQL

# What skills, work projects or achievements make you a strong candidate for this position?

The opportunity presented in this listing is very interesting, and I believe that my strong technical experience and education will make me a very competitive candidate for this position.

With a BS degree in Computer Programming, I have a full understanding of the full lifecycle of a software development project. I also have experience in learning and excelling at new technologies as needed.

Please see my resume for additional information on my experienced.

Date of birth: 03.10.1991

Email: taihanh0310@gmail.com

Phone: 0376460626 Skype: taihanh0310

## NGUYỄN TÀI HANH

### SUMMARIZES

I have had over 5 years working in Web development and had over 2 years working in ReactJs/React Native. I've taken part in some projects, especially Laravel/Yii2 web projects and React Native apps.

I have experienced in working with Japanese, Korean customer and working directly with many experienced engineers in other countries, especially I am good at web application, design database with schema optimization, full text search with Apache Solr (4.6)

I would like to work in competitive environment with professional colleagues, creation partners.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

### **BACK-END DEVELOPMENT**

- I have than about 4 years working experienced with PHP framework Laravel 4.2 to 5.x, Yii2
- Have than about 3 years working experienced with SOAP/WSDL and third party APIs and Cloud Platforms (AWS - Cloud Storage, Cloud Datastore, Cloud SQL)
- Have over 12 months working experienced with online payment gateway
  API from Vietnam providers and Foreign providers as stripe
- Have working experienced with Mysql innodb, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Apache Solr
- Solid commands with Git, Docker, PHP, linux OS

### FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

- Working experienced web design/coding (HTML5/SCSS /Bootstrap/Webpack)
- I have than about 2 years working experienced with React/ReduxJs and react native

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SENIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER AT DRCOM ASIA

#### JULY 2018 - Present

- Analyze requirement, estimate features which was assigned
- Code review and support technical for new members
- Helping teams deploy source code and build the ipa files

- Built new API services for external partners.
- Immediately attended to all reported customer issues regarding appbased and software solutions, delivered software patches when needed.
- Learned React Native/Redux-Persist/Basic Swift 4.2 and Atomic design for source code/template and design

### SENIOR PHP DEVELOPER AT IKORN SOLUTIONS

### March 2016 - May 2018

- Analyze requirement, estimate features which was assigned.
- Works closely with co-workers when coming up with database structures and writing code for new features.
- Improve performance, optimize code of existing features.
- Process and optimize SQL and cut down response time.
- Code review and support technical for new members.
- Organize any necessary meetings to progress team work (weekly, daily daily stand-up meetings)
- Weekly status report to managers and customers
- Learned ReactJS/ES6/lodash and Apache Solr version 4.6

### FRESHER/JUNIOR/MIDDLE DEVELOPER AT ISB VIETNAM

### Feb 2014 -Feb 2016

- Analyze requirements, design and develop, fix bugs the project
- Customize and optimize source code of the existing projects.
- Learned Agile / Scrum

### PROJECT SUMMARIES

### **EDA STANDALONE APP**

**Duration**: July 2018 – now

**Technologies and Tools**: React native 0.56, Redux, React persist, React run background, Laravel 5.2, Mysql 5.7, Symfony 1.4

**Project description**: VDW is an internal standalone app that supports sales representatives when meeting with their clients. The app contains all marketing materials and products' information of VDW. Based on sales reps' needs, the app also contains functions such as: email within the app, linking with other app(s)/website(s), and updating data by APIs.Presentations in the app functions as a CLM presentation with tracking feature.

The dashboard of the app facilitates users in organizing their behaviors in the "presentation." The dashboard lists down all available presentations, updated files in library, emails sent in the app.

User has to register to Relation Platform server to access to the application. After logging in, depending on user roles, user can see presentations by authorized regions, and roles. The following are the features offered by eDa Standalone App:

- Download libraries (pdf/image/youtube video) from provided API
- Structure data and allocate data in the proper place in the app
- Display content of the existing app in 2 languages: DE and EN
- Email template management
- Send API of email sent via the app to Relation Platform
- Open an app from the tool within the ipad device
- Track duration, frequency of usage, email sent via the app per presentation
- Perform analysis based on data tracked and export to a report
- Automatically check new available data and notify the user

### Working experienced:

- Design project structure and built an Web application using PHP laravel framework and React Native (0.56)
- Studied, evaluated, and proposed solutions to complex architectural challenges for the purpose of introducing new features.
- Designed, architected and wrote the front-end of our EDA application using React Native with over 38+ reusable components
- Optimized service layers, request queues and data news checking to handle download libraries and saving 15 minutes of presentation ( over 3gb data)
- Reported weekly to the 3 party with tracking on used the app. Tracking some feature: User login, download presentation, open screen, data opened and tracking emails with data attached
- Helped new members to integrate with the project's environment, have a thorough understanding of project's specifications and follow working process as soon as possible

### **FASHION ERP SOFTWARE**

**Duration**: Mar 2017 – Feb 2018

**Technologies and tools**: Laravel lumen 5.3, Bootstrap 3.x, ReactJS/Redux, cron job, Mysql, Pusher Notification

**Project description**: I have worked as Fashion ERP and lead a team of 9 engineers. We have completed about 15 business process improvement projects so far. The following are the features offered by FASHION ERP

- Product Lifecycle Management (PLM)
- Collaborative Supplier Portal
- Collaborative Vender Portal
- Shipping, Invoicing & Documentation
- Costing and Budget Planning
- Warehouse & Inventory Management
- Production Planning & Production
- Material Requirements Planning
- Purchase Requirements & Purchase order
- Integrated Accounting & Financials (Account receivable, Account Payable, Fixed Asets, General Ledger)
- Sampling Management
- Quality Control
- Centralized Document Approval centre
- Sales Orders
- Production Data
- Time & Activities Calendars
- HRM & KPI

**Team size**: 13 ( 9 dev, 1 Lead, 1 BA, 2 QC)

### **Working experienced:**

- Design project structure and built an Web application using PHP laravel lumen framework and ReactJs/redux (15.4)
- Worked with Docker for developing and deploying a content management website with big and complicated business (contains 250+ pages with over 180 + database tables)
- Worked closely with business analysts in defining technical specifications
- Clarifying the issues, estimating the process of project and reviewing other members' work.
- Organize any necessary meetings to progress team work (weekly, daily daily stand-up meetings).
- Weekly status report to manager and customer
- Helped new members to integrate with the project's environment, have a thorough understanding of project's specifications and follow working process as soon as possible

### PHARMACY SOFTWARE

**Duration**: December 2016 – Mar 2017

Technologies and tools: Laravel lumen 5.3, Bootstrap 3.x, ReactJS/Redux,

webpack module, Mysql

**Project description**: Pharmacy software is an one stop solution for billing, Inventory management and accounting needs. Software available for Pharma warehouse and retail business. The following are the features offered by Pharmacy software:

- Billing Features
- Purchase Features
- Discount & Schemes
- Document Printing
- Fully User-Configurable Invoicing
- Reports Features
- General Features (Calculator & Cash Return Adviser, Hot Keys, Single User & Multi User)
- Comprehensive Financial Accounting
- Inventory Management

### Team size: 5

### Working experienced:

- Design the source code structure and built an Web application using PHP laravel lumen framework and ReactJs
- Handled PHP backend development for dynamic database driven website
- API implemented and optimized the site for the best performance and user experience.
- Communicating directly with customer, clarifying the issues, estimating the process of project and reviewing other members' work.
- Helped new members to integrate with the project's environment, have a thorough understanding of project's specifications and follow working process as soon as possible.
- Supported continuous deployment to servers using SSH and Bitbucket.

### **QUARK PROJECT**

**Duration**: Feb 2016 - November 2016

Technologies and tools: Solr 4.6, MySql, Yii2, Smarty, Bootstrap 3.x, NodeJs

Team size: 10

Reference: <a href="http://www.quarkb2b.com/">http://www.quarkb2b.com/</a>

**Description**: Build the application which allow user see most of products (business to business model), which are sold by many suppliers. It allow user can also shop conveniently on-the-go via our mobile apps - browse, view, buy, track, and review your items anytime, anywhere. User can search and order to buy any product from the application. User can search via hashtag, brand, and band, to find the product needed on the application also.

### Working experienced

- Develop features across multiple sub features within Quark applications, including collaboration in requirements definition, prototyping, design, coding, testing and deployment
- Handled PHP backend development for dynamic database driven website
- Troubleshot problems with PHP and other web technologies (Notification, S3 image storage, PayPal)
- Maintained and developing an API system for integrating mobile applications on iOS and Android into the website
- Helped new members to integrate with the project's environment, have a thorough understanding of project's specifications and follow working process as soon as possible.
- Other duties from time to time as determined by Project Leader

### **HEALTHCARE MANAGEMENT**

Duration: Sept 2014 - Feb 2016

**Technologies and tools**: Laravel 4.2, PostgreSQL

Team size: 12

### Working experienced:

Sept 2014 - Feb 2016:

- Delivered a bug-free and error-free healthcare content management website related to sport players using Scrum and Continuous Integration for a provider in Japan.
- Worked with PHP Laravel framework and Docker for developing and deploying a content management website with big and complicated business (contains 30+ pages with over 100 database tables)

 Maintained and developing an API system for integrating mobile applications on iOS and Android into the website

### Jan 2015 - Feb 2016

- Became a Sub-leader of the working project team (with amount of members up to 12) within 4 months working in the project team
- Supported Project Leader in communicating directly with customer, clarifying the issues, estimating the process of project and reviewing other members' work
- Helped new members to integrate with the project's environment, have a thorough understanding of project's specifications and follow working process as soon as possible.
- Gave ideas that improve the workflow of the team, help raising performance of members and reducing wasted time.

### Eg:

Helped saving Team Leader's 30 minute to 1 hour per day by splitting his work on writing daily report to all other members;

Proposed cross-examination the work of members to reduce amount of bugs per sprint.

Contributed for the team that gained 4 / 5 points of satisfaction in the evaluation survey from a strict customer.

### EDUCATION **HCMUS**—**HCM** (2009-2013)